(忆往昔)
莉莉丝正打破66个封印
Lilith is tring to break the 66 seals
以使路西法能逃出地狱
To free lusifer from hell.
而路西法会让天启现世
Lusifer will bring the apocalypse
-妈  -萨姆
- Mom.  - Sam
-对不起  -为什么
- I'm sorry  - For what?
就因为我体内有恶魔的血吗
Does this mean I have demon blood in me?
我不想再当学校里的怪人了  哪怕就一次
I don't wanna be the freak for once Dean
我想做个正常人
I wanna be normal.
迪恩  你弟弟走上一条不归路
You brother is heading down a dangerous road, Dean.
知道你已经做得有多离谱了吗
Do you even know how far of the reservation you've gone.
背离常人  背离人类多远了吗
How for from normal, from human?
如果我不认识你
If I didn't know you.
我会猎杀你
I would hunter you.
是想问我是否知道恶魔之血的事吗
What if I know about the demon blood?
你没告诉迪恩
You did't tell Dean.
该死的你到底在哪里  露比
Where the hell are you, Ruby?
我喝完了  打给我  我还要更多
I'm all out. call me. I need more.
这都是为了你好
This is for your own good.
哥们儿？
Guys?
嘿  哥们儿  这一点也不好笑
Hey -- guys, this isn't funny!
嘿
Hey!
(如今)
好了  让我出去  这一点也不好笑
Okay. Let me out. This is not funny.
你TM说对了
Damn straight.
迪恩  搞什么  这太疯狂了
Dean. Come on, this is crazy.
不  直到你能戒掉恶魔血
No. Not until you dry out.
对不起  我不该对你说谎
Look, I'm sorry. I shouldn't have lied to you.
求你...打开门
Just...open the door.
你不必道歉  这不是你的错
You don't have to apologize. It's not your fault.
你一次又一次的说谎
It's not your fault that you lied to me
不是你的错
over and over again.
我现在明白了  你是无法自控
I get it now. You couldn't help it.
我可不是什么瘾君子
I'm not some junkie!
真的吗？
Really?
我想我刚刚想起你
I guess I've just imagined
最近那些疯狂的举动
how strung out you've been lately.
事实上你把这当作了
You're actually trying to twist this
一场滑稽的戒毒行动
into some kind of ridiculous drug intervention?
死鸭子嘴还硬
If it smells like a duck.
迪恩  我不是因为上瘾而喝恶魔血
Dean, I'm not drinking the demon blood for kicks.
我正变得强大到可以杀死莉莉丝
I'm getting strong enough to kill lilith.
-强大?  -是啊
- Strong? - Yeah.
恶魔血不会让你变强大
It's about as far away from strong
只会让你变得
as you can get.
虚弱  绝望  可悲
Try weak. Try desperate. Pathetic.
能杀死莉莉丝才是关键
Killing Lilith is what matters.
或者你太过于自以为是
Or are you so busy being self-righteous
而忘了她
You forgot about her?
莉莉丝一定会要死的  我和鲍比一定会杀了他
Oh, Lilith's gonna die. Bobby and I will kill her.
不是和你
But not with you.
-你不是认真的吧  -恭喜你答对了  萨姆
- You're not serious. - Congrats, Sammy.
在对抗天启时  你绝对会坐冷板凳的
You just bought yourself a benchwarmer seat to the apocalypse.
迪恩  不 等等
Dean. No, wait.
回来
Come back here!
迪恩  放我出去
Dean! Let me out of here!
让我出去  迪恩
Let me out! Dean!
哥们儿  快下来  有东西来了
Guys! Get down here! Something's coming!
你好啊  萨姆
Hello, Sam.
真高兴再次见到你
It's a pleasure to see you again.
貌似你落到我手里了
And looks like I have you all to myself here.
天哪
Goodness.
我们要如何度过这段时光
How will we pass the time?
不要
Don't.
不  不  不要  不要
No, no, don't. Don't.
啊不要
Ah, don't.
不要啊  住手
Don't! Stop!
阿拉斯泰尔...
Alastair...
求你了
Ohh! Please!
Please.
出人意料的礼貌啊
So polite all of a sudden.
很好
Very nice.
谢谢你的配合
I appreciate that.
不  不  阿拉斯泰尔  不 不 不
No, no. Alastair. No, no, no.
不
No.
啊不
Aah! No!
求你了  求你了
Please! please!
不  不 住手
No! no! Stop!
这还要持续多久
How long is this gonna go on?
让我们来看看恶魔戒毒手册
Here, let me look it up in my demon-detox manual.
哦  等一下  没人写过
Oh, wait. No one ever wrote one.
所以没人知道要持续多久
No telling how long it'll take.
或是萨姆能不能挺过这一切
Hell, or if Sam will even live through it.
喂
Hello?
去死吧  卢夫斯
Suck dirt and die, Rufus.
你再打我电话  我会杀了你
You call me again, I'll kill you.
卢夫斯怎么了
What's up with Rufus?
他知道了
He knows.
我很忙  你这混蛋  没事别烦我
I'm busy, you son of bitch. This better be important.
答案是"是"  那是幻觉
The answer's "YES." You're hallucinating.
对了  就是我
That's right. It's me.
或者说  就是你
Or, I mean, it's you.
我疯了
I'm losing my mind.
完全正确
Definitely.
你想要什么
What do you want?
一个解释
An explanation.
你怎么能这么对我
How could you do this to me?
我本以为我们会变得正常的
I thought we were gonna be normal.
我试过了  真的
I tried. I did.
结果没成功
It didn't pan out that way.
对不起  孩子
Sorry, kid.
"Sorry, kid"?
这就是你想说的  这是我们一直想要的
That's what you have to say? It's all we ever wanted.
我们差点就成功了
We were so close!
你离开了老爸  你放弃捕猎
Y-you got away from dad. You quit hunting.
你曾将要成为一名律师然后结婚生子
You were gonna become a lawyer and get married.
-你为什么把事情搞砸了?  -听着
- Why did you blow it?! - Look!
他们杀了杰西卡
They killed jessica.
是啊
Yeah.
如果你没和迪恩离开的话
And if you hadn't run off with Dean,
如果你留下保护她的话
If you'd been there to protect her,
她就会活下来
She'd still be alive.
我知道
I know.
你认为杰西卡希望你变成这样吗
Think Jess would want you to turn into this?
她爱你
She loved you.
你觉得把她作为借口
You think she would be happy
她会高兴么
you using her as an excuse?
我很抱歉  真的
I'm sorry. I am.
人生不会按照你的想法去发展
But life doesn't turn out the way you thought it would
当你14岁的时候
When you were 14 years old.
我们就于众不同了
We were never gonna be normal.
我们永远逃避不了
We were never gonna get away.
成熟点吧
Grow up.
也许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
也许根本没有...解决之道
Maybe there's... no escape.
终究...
After all...
你怎么可能摆脱你的本性
How can you run from what's inside you?
消息  不好的消息
The news. And the news ain't good.
这就是卢夫斯打电话来的原因吗
This is what Rufus called about?
基韦斯特有十个物种灭绝
"Key west sees 10 species go extinct"?
是的
Yep.
另外  阿拉斯加  15人捕鱼小组
Plus, Alaska -- 15-man fishing crew,
集体失明...原因不详
All stricken blind -- cause unknown.
纽约...
New york --
老师持枪  反锁大门
Teacher goes postal, locks the door,
恰好杀死了66个小孩
Kills exactly 66 kids.
这些都是在一天之内完成
All this in a single day?
我查过了
I looked them up.
毫无疑问的  这些都是封印
There's no doubt about it. they're all Seals.
迅速地破坏
Breaking -- fast.
还剩多少封印
How many are left?
谁知道呢  不会很多的
Who knows? Can't be many.
你的天使伙伴在什么鬼地方啊
Where the hell are your angel pals?
我去问谁啊
You tell me.
我只是在想
I'm just wondering...
想什么
What?
天启越来越近了
With the apocalypse being nigh and all,
现在我们有时间
Is now really the right time to be
去弄这种家庭剧么
Having this little domestic drama of ours?
你这话是什么意思啊
What do you mean?
我也不喜欢这样做  但...
Well, I don't like this any more than you do, but...
萨姆能杀死恶魔
Sam can kill demons.
他能阻止世界末日的来临
He's got a shot at stopping armageddon.
然后呢  牺牲萨姆的生命  灵魂
So, what, sacrifice Sam's life, his soul,
为了更美好的事业吗
For the greater good?
这就是你想说的吗
Is that what you're saying?
时光流逝  就让我们把萨姆当做原子弹使用吗
Times are bad, so let's use Sam as a nuclear warhead?
我知道你讨厌我做这样的建议
Look, I know you hate me for suggesting it.
我也不喜欢这个建议
I hate me for suggesting it.
我把他当做我的儿子一样爱着
I love that boy like a son.
我想说的是  他现在在这里
All I'm saying is, maybe he's here right now
而不是在战场上
Instead of on the battlefield,
因为我们十分爱他
'cause we love him too much.
可怜的宝贝
Poor baby.
妈
Mom!
萨姆
Sam.
你看起来糟糕透了
You look just awful.
你就说吧
Let's hear it.
走吧
Go ahead.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你很失望
You're disappointed.
你从不会认为我...
You never thought I'd...
用这种方式证明
...turn out this way.
我是个...
I'm a...
没有价值的儿子
Pisspoor excuse for a son.
你心都碎了
Your heart is broken.
我说的对吗
Am I close?
不对
Not at all.
你在做着正确的事  萨姆
You're doing the right thing, Sam.
你所做的事非常勇敢
What you're doing is brave.
你不是疯了  而是很务实的做法
You're not being crazy. you're being practical.
萨姆  我为你感到骄傲
Sam, I am so proud of you.
但是...
But...
但是  迪恩他
But...Dean.
你哥哥不理解
Your brother doesn't understand.
我从小就被培养成一个猎人
I was raised a hunter, from a long line.
我们清楚这会是个艰难的抉择
We understand that there are gonna be hard choices.
不惜一切代价完成任务
And we do what we have to to get the job done.
我们的家族是被诅咒的
Yes, our family is cursed.
但你
But you...
你能把这诅咒转化成天赋
You have the power to turn it into a gift.
你能用这个来对抗他们
You can use it against them.
为了报仇吗
For revenge?
不  是为了正义
No, for justice.
你知道你有多害怕
I know how scared you are.
在...
What's...
在我身体里的...
In me...
妈
Mom?
是罪恶
It's... evil.
你也是知道的
And you know it.
如果它比我还强大呢
What if it's stronger than me?
看我呀  如果迪恩是对的呢
Look at me. what if Dean's right?
迪恩永远不会知道你有多么强大
Dean can never know how strong you are...
因为迪恩很弱小
...because Dean is weak.
看他对你所做的一切
Look at what he's done to you.
把你锁在这里  他吓坏了
Locking you in here? He's terrified.
他冲昏头脑了
He's in over his head.
你应该离开他自己走下去
You have to go on without him.
你必须这样去做
You have what it takes.
你必须去杀死莉莉丝
You have to kill Lilith.
即使它杀了我
Even if it kills me.
让我的死有点意义吧
Make my death mean something.
我指望着你  萨姆
I'm counting on you, Sam.
别让任何人任何事阻碍了你的道路
Don't let anyone or anything get in your way.
迪恩也不行
Not even Dean.
差不多是时候了
Well, it's about time.
我在这里喊了2个半小时
I've been screaming myself hoarse out here
嗓子都喊哑了
For about 2 1/2 hours now.
你想怎样
What do you want?
你可以从解释
Well, you can start
在伊利诺伊发生的事开始
With what the hell happened in Illinois.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
别说废话了
Cut the crap.
你必须告诉我些什么
You were gonna tell me something.
没什么值得说的
Well, nothing of import.
你在天堂被菊爆了么
You got ass-reamed in heaven.
-什么叫"没什么值得说的"  -迪恩
- But it was not "of import"?  - Dean.
我不能说
I can't.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
告诉我你究竟为什么召唤我
Get to the reason you really called me.
是关于萨姆的吧
It's about Sam, right?
他能做到吗
Can he do it?
能杀了莉莉丝  阻止天启的到来吗
Kill lilith, stop the apocalypse?
有可能
Possibly, yes.
但正如你所知道的
But as you know,
他必须付出些代价
He'd have to take certain steps.
把恶魔血当毒品吸么
Crank up the hell-blood regimen.
当他强大能杀死莉莉丝时
Consuming the amount of blood it would take to kill lilith
恶魔血会永久性地改变你的弟弟
Would change your brother forever.
最有可能的是  他会成为下一个
Most likely, he would become the next creature
你必须杀掉的生物
That you would feel compelled to kill.
这事不会会就这样过去的  迪恩
There's no reason this would have to come to pass, Dean.
我们相信的是你  迪恩
We believe it's you, Dean,
不是你的弟弟
Not your brother.
唯一困扰我们的事情是
The only question for us is
你是否会接受这样的事实
Whether you're willing to accept it.
站起来接受你的使命
Stand up and accept your role.
你是那个能阻止这一切的人
You are the one who will stop it.
如果我做了  萨姆就不用做了吗
If I do this... Sammy doesn't have to?
从好的那一面讲  是的
If it gives you comfort to see it that way.
天啊  你这几天太人渣了
God, you're a dick these days.
好吧  我入伙
Fine. I'm in.
你打算全心全意地
You give yourself over wholly
服务上帝和他的天使吗
To the service of god and his angels?
愿意
Yeah. exactly.
重复一遍
Say it.
我将全心全意
I give myself over wholly
侍奉上帝
To serve god...
和你们
And you guys.
你发誓会听从他的意愿和指令
You swear to follow his will and his word
迅速地  顺从地
As swiftly and obediently
像听从你的父亲一样吗
As you did your own father's?
是的  我发誓
Yes. I swear.
然后呢
Now what?
耐心等待
Now you wait.
到时候我们会来找你
And we call on you when it's time.
来人啊  救命啊
Guys! help!
救命啊  放我出去
Help! let me out of here!
迪恩
Dean!
如果我说错了  你可以指正
Now, correct me if I'm wrong,
但是你竟然愿意成为天使的贱人
But you willingly signed up to be the angels' bitch?
对不起  "屁精"是不是好点
I'm sorry. you prefer "sucker"?
你说了那么多他们的事情
After everything you said about them,
你现在又相信他们了
Now you trust them?
别这样  鲍比  相信我
Come on, give me a little credit, Bobby.
我从来没相信过他们
I've never trusted them less.
感觉他们像是从火神星来的黑暗政客
I mean, they come on like shady politicians from planet vulcan!
那为什么你...
Well, then why in the hell --
我有选择的余地吗
Because what other option do I have?!
是选择相信天使  还是让萨姆相信恶魔
It's either trust the angels, or let Sammy trust a demon?!
我懂了
I see your point.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
好像安静的有点奇怪
That's a little too much nothing.
他会不会在装
What if he's faking?
你真的认为他会吗
You really think he would?
我认为他什么都做得出来
I think he'd do anything.
绝对不是在装
That ain't faking.
为了他的安全  不得不把他绑起来
We're gonna have to tie him down for his own safety.
迪恩  你在听吗
Dean? you with me?
迪恩  趁他还没再次发作
Dean! before he has another fit!
好的  赶快把事情办妥
Yeah, yeah! let's just get it over with!
我们不得不这么做
We had to.
恶魔的血把你在房间里乱扔
The demon blood was flinging you all over the room.
萨姆  告诉我
Tell me something, Sam.
为什么这么作践自己
Why did you do this to yourself?
你知道原因
You know why.
没错
Right.
杀死莉莉丝  是个重要的借口
"Kill Lilith." the big excuse.
但是为什么
But why?
为了报仇吗
What, revenge?
对吗
Right?
当然
Of course.
报仇的原因呢
Revenge for what?
因为她送我进地狱吗
For sending me to hell?
你有没有看到  我回来了
Did you happen to notice I'm back?
活生生得回来了
Alive and kicking.
-到底是为什么  -为什么
- So what's the point? - The point?
阻止该死的天启  怎么样
How about stop the damn apocalypse?
那是我的任务  不是你的
My gig! not yours!
天使说的  记得吗
The angels said so, remember?
上帝选择了我
God picked me, man.
你还有没有好一点的理由
So, have you got any other fantastic excuses?
我再问你一次
I'm gonna ask one more time.
我们确信现在做的事情是对的吗
Are we absolutely sure we're doing the right thing?
鲍比  你也看到了他的样子
Bobby, you saw what was happening to him down there.
恶魔的血在害他
The demon blood is killing him.
不  是我们在害他
No, it isn't. We are.
-什么  -对不起
- What? - I'm sorry.
我看不下去了
I can't bite my tongue any longer.
我们正在害他
We're killing him.
把他关在下面
Keeping him locked up down there.
这种直截了当的方法不起作用
This "cold turkey" thing isn't working.
如果他得不到他所需要的
If,if he doesn't get what he needs...
很快
Soon...
萨姆撑不了多久
Sam's not gonna last much longer.
不
No.
我不会给他恶魔的血  绝对不给
I'm not giving him demon blood. I won't do it.
如果他死了呢
And if he dies?
至少他死的时候还是个人
Then at least he dies human!
萨姆  我知道你喝血的真正原因了
I know why you really drink that blood, Sam.
别管我
Just leave me alone.
让你感觉更强大  天下无敌
Makes you feel strong. invincible.
成为3只小猪里的大灰狼
A big bad wolf in a world of little pigs.
迪恩  你错了
No. you're wrong, Dean.
还不止这个吧  是吗
It's more than that, isn't it?
因为你整个人生都感觉不一样了
It's because your whole life, you felt different.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
别说了
Stop.
看来我说对了
Oh, I hit a little close to home, huh?
和其他孤独的孩子一样
Not different because you were some...lonely kid
-还是因为你的畸形家庭  -别说了
- Or because of your weirdo family. - Stop it.
-因为你是个怪物  -闭嘴
- Because you're a monster. - Shut up!
-闭嘴  -你一直是个怪物
- Just shut the hell up! - You were always a monster.
只有当你吃下更多的毒药
And you only feel right
和邪恶的时候你才会感到舒服
When you're sucking down more poison and more evil!
我可以马上替他死
I would die for him in a second.
但是我不会让他作践自己
But I won't let him do this to himself.
我做不到
I can't.
我想这就是我的底线了
I guess I found my line.
我不会让自己的弟弟变成怪物
I won't let my brother turn into a monster.
萨姆  你是一个怪物
Monster, Sam. You're a monster.
迪恩  不要
Dean, no.
我想尽办法装作我们是兄弟
I tried so hard to pretend that we were brothers,
你不是我们要猎杀的恶魔
That you weren't one of the filthy things that we hunt.
但是我们不是同一个物种
But we're not even the same species.
-对我来说  你什么都不是  -别这么说
- You're nothing to me. - Don't say that to me.
不许你对我这么说
Don't you say that to me.
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
Someone here?
你做了什么
What did you do?
安娜  你不该来
You shouldn't have come, Anna.
你为什么要放走萨姆·温彻斯特
Why would you let out Sam Winchester?
这是我的命令
Those were my orders.
命令
Orders?
卡西  你看到他的样子了
Cass...you saw him.
他在喝恶魔的血
He's drinking demon blood.
这比我们想象的更糟糕
It's so much worse than we thought.
迪恩试图阻止他
Dean was trying to stop him.
你真的不该来
You really shouldn't have come.
萨姆
Unh-unh, Sam.
你唯一能做的是跟我回去
The only place you're going is back inside with me.
不要
No.
妈的  孩子
Damn it, boy.
你不会开枪的  鲍比
You won't shoot me, bobby.
别考验我
Don't test me.
你不会这么做的
You won't do it.
你做不到
You can't do it.
我们是想要帮你啊  萨姆
We're trying to help you, sam.
那就开枪吧
Then shoot.
他是怎么逃出来的
How in the hell did he get out?
可能有帮忙
Maybe he had help.
这间房子到处都是打破的魔鬼封印
Room full of busted devil's traps.
魔鬼
Demons?
露比
Ruby
我是这么想的
that'd be my guess.
她怎么可能碰这扇门
How did she even touch the door?
你觉得她用了巫术吗
You think she's got the mojo?
我想不是
I didn't think so.
我也搞不清楚
I don't know, man.
他是怎么逃出来的
Well, what difference does it make?
有什么关系
How he got gone
最重要的是  他要去哪里
Ain't as important as where he got gone to.
没错  我跟你说
Yeah, well, I'll tell you one thing.
现在  我希望那个家伙是露比
At this point, I hope he's with ruby.
为什么
Why?
因为她是我下一个要铲除的恶魔
'cause killing her's the next big item on my to-do list.
我还以为你只给天使做事
I thought you were on call for angel duty.
我随时待命
I am on call --
在车上  在我去杀了那婊子的路上
In my car, on my way to murder the bitch.
-还有一件事  -什么
One thing. what?
萨姆不想被找到
Sam don't want to be found.
说明他会很难找
Which means he's gonna be damn near impossible to find.
知道了  等着瞧吧
Yeah, we'll see.
蜜月套房  不会吧  真是受宠若惊啊
Honeymoon suite. really, I'm flattered.
你把我从那房子里放出来的吗
Did you bust me out of that room?
我怎么有这能耐啊
How could i, sam?
那整个房间本身就是用来困我的
The whole thing's engineered to bite me in the ass.
那我是怎么出来的
Then how did I get out of there?
我不知道  也不想知道
I don't know. I don't want to know.
你出来了  这才是最重要的
You're out. that's all that matters.
很高兴看到你
I'm glad you're here.
真的吗  那你他妈去哪儿啦
Yeah? where the hell have you been?
我已经尽快赶过来了
I got here as quick as I could.
我是说这三个星期  我一直打你电话
I mean the past three weeks! I've been calling you!
我在忙着把莉莉丝找出来
I've been pretty deep in it, trying to dig out lilith.
有时候我没空查我的语音信箱
Sometimes I can't sit around and check my voicemail.
对不起  让你受伤了
I'm sorry you're hurting.
真的
Really.
我不知道迪恩会对你做出这种事情
I had no idea that dean would do that to you.
我也没想到
You and me both.
你订这房间不会只是想打动我吧
You didn't book this joint just to impress me, did you?
迪恩会找到我的
Dean's gonna come after me.
他知道我的习惯
And he knows my habits,
我的别名  一切
My aliases, everything.
他清楚我会住哪家旅馆
He knows exactly which motel I'd pick.
还有房间
Hence the room.
要用尽方法将他甩掉
Whatever it takes to shake him.
这不件容易的事  我是说...
Well, it won't be easy. I mean...
他比任何人都要了解你
He knows you better than anyone.
没他想的那么了解
Not as well as he thinks.
我知道  真可悲
You know, it's sad.
什么
What?
让你们俩兄弟反目成仇
That things have gotten this bad between you two.
警察找到了我的车子
Police found my car.
被丢在了北达科他州詹姆斯敦的巷子里
Abandoned in an alley in jamestown, north dakota.
这么说  他换车了
Well, he's switching up.
在詹姆斯敦有没有什么车被偷
Any other cars stolen in jamestown?
两辆
Two.
1999的本田汽车
1999 honda civic --
蓝色  很好而且是匿名的
Blue -- nice and anonymous,
是萨姆喜欢的款
Like sam likes.
另一辆呢
What was the other one?
白色的05凯迪拉克
White '05 escalade with custom rims.
围着霓虹灯
It's a neon sign.
你说对了  他不可能要那辆车
You're right. he'd never take that.
这正是他会偷的
Which is exactly what he did.
你觉得会吗
You think?
我了解他
I know that kid.
好吧  我们就去那个方向
All right, I'll head in that direction.
你留在这里  继续搜索警方数据
You stay here, ride the police databases.
我们得尽快找到他
We got to find him quick.
你的胃口越来越大了
Your appetite's gotten much bigger.
这意味这什么
What's that supposed to mean?
萨姆  没事的  是件好事
Sam, relax. it's okay. it's good.
只是说明你越来越强大了  仅此而已
It just means you're getting stronger. that's all.
意味着你已经足以铲除莉莉丝
It means you're strong enough to kill lilith.
时间也刚刚好
Just in time, too,
因为最后的封印正在打开
Because the final seals are breaking.
还有多少个
how many are left?
-三个  两个  -什么
Three? two? what?!
那天使都到哪儿去了
Well, where are the angles?
遛狗吧  管他们去哪
Screwing the pooch, wherever they are.
重要的是  现在我们是一步步
The point is, it's looking more and more
接近最后的封印了
Like we're getting down to the final seal.
而且我发现一个天大的秘密
And I found out something big.
什么
What?
第六十六个封印
Seal 66?
不是任何一个恶魔都能打破的
It can't be broken by just any demon.
事实上  只有路西法的第一大徒弟才能做到
Apparently, only Lucifer's first can do it.
"路西法的第一大徒弟"
"Lucifer's first"?
恶魔的主日学校故事
Demon sunday-school story.
比起天使来  上帝更宠爱世人
God prefers humans to angels.
路西法嫉妒了  然后他想出一个办法
Lucifer gets jealous. and then he gets creative.
他扭曲人类的灵魂并且教唆他们
And he twists and tempts a human soul
成为第一个恶魔   就像是对上帝的公然挑衅
Into the very first demon -- as a "screw you" to god.
这就是他被关起来的首要原因
It's what got him locked up in the first place.
那个是莉莉丝吗
That was lilith?
她比看上去要老多了
She's way older than she looks.
等一下  这么说...
Wait, so...
如果莉莉丝是唯一能打破最后一道封印的恶魔
If lilith is the only one who can break the final seal,
如果我能及时抓到她
If I get to her in time...
那么路西法就不可能逃出那笼子 没错
Then Lucifer never busts out of his cage -- exactly.
太棒了  你知道她在哪儿吗
Great. you figure out where she is?
那婊子能躲起来
That bitch can hide.
可是我还是找到了线索
But I finally have a lead
从一个或许能帮助我们的人身上
On someone who might be able to help us.
我瞄上了莉莉丝的随从
I closed in on a member of lilith's entourage.
你们可以称呼她作...私人厨师
You might call her a... personal chef.
厨师？  不会吧
Chef? seriously?
她吃什么啊
What does she eat?
你不会想知道的
You don't want to know.
听说发生在圣保罗的骇闻了吗
Did you hear about that horrible thing at St. Paul's?
没呐
No.
一个妇产科护士
One of the neonatal nurses
抱走了两个刚刚出世的婴儿
Walked right off the unit with two babies.
你跟我开玩笑的吧
You are kidding me.
向天发誓这千真万确
Swear to god.
一个工作了17年的老护士
Worked there 17 years,
突然有一天  冷不防地  就抱走了孩子
Then one day, out of the blue, she just does it.
这真是太毛骨悚然了
That's just horrifying.
事后她尽然说
Now she's saying
完全不记得发生了什么事儿
That she doesn't even remember what happened.
说自己像是着了魔似的
Like she was possessed.
真鬼扯
Nuts.
同意
I know.
谁会那么残忍向他们下手啊
Who could ever lay a finger on them?
同意
I know.
他们是那么甜美
They're just delicious.
那就是说  现在有个嗜美味恶魔护士了
So, our demon gourmet nurse...
你确定吗
...you sure?
绝对是她
She'll be there.
明晚就轮到她上夜班了
Graveyard shift. tomorrow night.
在此期间
In the meantime,
如果想强大到足以对付莉莉丝
If you're gonna be strong enough to kill Lilith,
你该找比我更强大的恶魔才行了
You're gonna need more than I can give you now.
萨姆
Sam.
别那样  没事的
Come on. it's okay.
我知道  我需要更多的
I know, I need more.
我知道  我很清楚
I-I get it. I know it's okay.
只不过
I just...
我只是希望他能信任我  知道吗
I wish he'd trusted me, you know?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不过是希望
I just hope...
等这一切结束之后
You know, when all this is over...
还有机会弥补
I hope we can fix things.
警察在麋鹿河外的河渠里发现了爬云梯
The cops found the escalade in a ditch outside Elk River.
-距我现在的地方多远  -几小时的路程
- How far away am I? - couple of hours.
我查了气象资料  又打了几个电话
I pulled up a weather map, made some calls.
距你那儿不远的  冷泉镇
There's a town not far from there, Coldspring,
显然有恶魔出没的迹象
Lighting up with demon signs.
那可是个观光胜地啊
That's a good place to look.
嘿  听着
Hey, listen.
-什么  -记住我们找萨姆
- What? - us finding Sam?
目的是为了让他悬崖勒马
That's got to be about getting him back,
而不是逼他无路可退
Not pushing him away.
当然
Right.
我知道你气得爆肝  迪恩
I know you're mad, Dean.
我了解那种感受
I understand.
生气归生气
You got a right to be.
但  我不得不说一句
But... I'm just saying --
无论如何都别硬碰硬
Be good to him anyway.
好好和他沟通下
You got to get through to him.
别
No!
放了她
Let her go!
别紧张
Just take it easy.
你们俩会来这儿准备干一票
Wow, that must have been some party you two had going,
却不通知我一声
Considering how hard you tried to keep me from crashing it.
要找到你们确实很困难  不过
Well, solid try, but...
我还是赶来了
Here I am.
迪恩  你能来我很高兴
Dean, I'm glad you're here.
好了  我们先谈谈这儿的情况
Look...let's just talk about this.
等灭了她  我们再慢慢聊
Soon as she's dead, we can talk all you want.
露比  快离开这儿
Ruby, get out of here.
她哪儿都别想去
She's not going anywhere.
她就是始作俑者  萨姆
She's poison, Sam!
事实并非你想得那样  迪恩
It's not what you think, Dean.
瞧瞧她对你做得一切
Look what she did to you!
她总是每隔数周就会自动现身又再消失
Well, she up and vanishes, weeks at a time,
扔下来痛得死去活来的你跑掉
Leaves you cracking out for another hit!
她是在打探莉莉丝的下落
She was looking for Lilith!
那正是法语里面一个说法
That is french for
抓住了软肋自然就能控制你
"manipulating your ass 10 ways from sunday."
你错了  迪恩
You're wrong, Dean.
萨姆  你这是在自欺欺人
Sam, you're lying to yourself.
我只是  为你着想
I just... want you to be okay.
换作是我你也会做同样的事
You would do the same for me.
你应该明白的
You know you would.
听我说
Just listen.
听我把话说完
Just listen for a second.
我们发现了一个和莉莉丝极相似的恶魔
We got a lead on a demon close to Lilith.
一起来吧  迪恩
Come with us, Dean.
我们一起对付这个恶魔
We'll do this together.
那听起来好极了
That sounds great.
但只能是你和我
As long as it's you and me.
那恶魔贱人就是个老鼠屎
Demon bitch is a deal breaker.
去和她吻个别  我们立马离开这儿
You kiss her goodbye, we can go right now.
我办不到
I can't.
迪恩  我需要她  需要她帮我灭了莉莉丝
Dean, I need her -- to help me kill Lilith.
我清楚现在你无法接受这一切
I know you can't wrap your head around it.
但或许  将来的某一天  你终会理解
But maybe, one day... you'll understand.
我是唯一能够阻止天启降世的人  迪恩
I'm the only one who can do this, Dean.
不  你绝不是能够阻止这一切的人
No, you're not the one who's gonna do this.
对啊  我差点儿就忘了
Right. that's right. I forgot.
天使认为你才是命定之人
The angels think it's you.
你觉得我办不到吗
You don't think I can?
是的  你办不到
No. You can't.
你根本就不够强大
You're not strong enough.
你小子说什么呢
And who the hell are you?
我只是实事求是罢了
I'm being practical here.
而我已经做好了准备
I'm doing what needs to be done.
是吗
Yeah?
你不会就是指那该死的吸血吧
You're not gonna do a single damn thing.
别再对我指手画脚了  迪恩
Stop bossing me around, Dean!
听着
Look.
过去的岁月  我都以你马首是瞻
My whole life, you take the wheel,
都是你说了算
You call the shots.
就因为你是我大哥我对你是百分百地信任
And I trust you because you are my brother.
此刻  我请求你
Now, I am asking you,
就这一次
For once...
相信我
Trust me.
不行
No.
你根本不明白自己都在干嘛  萨姆
You don't know what you're doing, Sam.
不  我清楚得很
Yes, I do.
那就更糟了
Then that's worse!
为什么  听着  所以我才告诉你
Why? look, I'm telling you --
因为这跟你做了什么没关系
Because it's not something that you're doing!
而是你究竟算什么
It's what you are!
说白了
It means...
什么
What?
别停下
No.
说出来
Say it.
说白了你就是个怪物
It means you're a monster.
你根本就不了解我
You don't know me.
你从没了解过我
You never did.
更永远无法了解
And you never will.
一旦踏出这个门
You walk out that door...
就永远也别想回来了
Don't you ever come back.